# **Guillermo Paz**

#### **Front End Developer**

#### **About me**

I am a front end developer from Buenos Aires, Argentina.

I know and love the good parts of JavaScript. I love taking advantage of awesome new browser features, without breaking the experience on IE8. I can write CSS that works on all modern browsers (IE8+, FF, Chrome, Safari).

I keep a close eye on trends and innovations in the field of browser interfaces, JavaScript development and web technologies. I love and desire to experiment with new technologies.

#### **Personal Details**

Birth: May 28, 1988

Address: Buenos Aires, Argentina E-mail: guille87paz@gmail.com Website: http://pazguille.me

### **Professional Experience**

2008-Present	Frontend Developer - MercadoLibre I'm a Front End Developer at MercadoLibre. I build Chico UI (MercadoLibre's UI framework). I review the front end code. Beside, I research the best practices and teach them to others front end teams to improve
	their code. I give speeches about web standards, best practices and how to improve your frontend code.
2007-Present	Independent web developer, front end developer.  Training and doing workshops about open web standards. Occasionally freelancing.
2007–2008	Customer Service - MercadoLibre

## **Specialties**

I have a broad understanding of the full Open Web Stack of technologies:

- Expert level knowledge of the JavaScript language.
- Expert level knowledge of jQuery.
- Expert understanding of web technologies (object-oriented JavaScript, HTML, CSS).
- Expert level knowledge of HTML y CSS.
- Expert at writing semantic and well formed HTML.

- Experience at developing JavaScript libraries.
- Experience at writing vanilla Javascript.
- Experience with JavaScript libraries (jQuery, Modernizr, Backbone, Underscore).
- Experience with the latest and greatest web standards, including HTML5 and CSS3 (W3C).
- Experience at working with REST APIs.
- Experience at testing and developing across multiple browsers while maintaining a consistent experience.
- Experience at working with graceful degradation y progressive enhancement.
- Experience with Responsive Web Design.
- Experience with NodeJS, Express, Jade, SocketIO and Mongoose.
- Experience with GIT (I absolutely love Github).

#### **Education**

2008–2011	Diseñador y Administrador de Sitios Web. Instituto de Arte Multimedial Da Vinci.
2006–2007	First 2 years of <b>Licenciatura en Análisis de Sistemas</b> . Universidad de Buenos Aires.
2001–2005	Bachiller con Capacitación Laboral en Comunicación Social. Instituto Ana María Janer.

#### **Honors and Awards**

August 2012	Winner of Facebook Developers World Hack Latin America 2012. The best
	overall application of Latin America - Buenos Aires, Argentina.

## **Projects**

November 2012	<b>Viewport</b> : It is a component to ease viewport management. You can get the dimensions of the viewport and beyond, which can be quite helpful to perform some checks with JavaScript.
May 2012	Jvent: Event Emitter Class for the browser based on NodeJS EventEmitter.
June 2009	<b>Chico UI</b> : MercadoLibre's a big and complex web site with a lot of needs. Every development and design team needed to be able to build quality and consistent web apps using an agile development process. So we had to find a way to unify the process and guarantee design pattern and user experience quality for every team. And Chico was born.

More of my open source libraries and projects can be found in my Github account.

## **Speaking**

May 2012	I gave a speech at <b>JSconf Argentina</b> about Chico UI and how it helps
	MercadoLibre to improve its code using the best practices of frontend and

## Languages

Spanish: Native

• English: Intermediate

## **Professional interests**

- Open web standards
- Front-end architecture
- Web Usability & Accessibility
- Web Development Education
- API design
- Graphic Design